<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Macro Calculator</string>
<<<<<<< Updated upstream
=======
    <string name="MacroText" />
    <string name="MacroText1">
        All carbohydrates are eventually broken down into glucose, which is the main energy source for your body.
        In fact, specific organs, such as your brain, need glucose in order to function properly. Your body can make
        glucose out of necessity from proteins using gluconeogenesis. Beyond be your main energy source, there are
        carbohydrates that help synthesize specific amino acids (protein building blocks) and allow for consistent
        bowel movements. Fiber is a type of carbohydrate that cannot be broken down by your GI tract. Therefore, this nutrient
        does not give you energy, but it does help rid your body of waste and keeps your intestinal tract healthy. Carbohydrates
        are not all created equally. Some are considered simple carbohydrates and others are complex. Protein allows your body to
        grow, build and repair tissues, and protect lean body mass (your muscle mass) Protein is composed of amino acids. Amino acids
        are the building blocks of protein. There are 2 types of amino acids: non-essential and essential. Non-essential amino acids
        are not required to be consumed through the diet as your body can actually make these. Essential amino acids are required
        through your diet. Essential amino acids can either be used on their own or in some cases they are transformed into a
        non-essential amino acid. Protein rich foods include meat, poultry, fish, egg, milk, cheese, or other types of animal
        by-product foods. These protein sources contain all of your essential amino acids. This does not mean you have to eat
        animal foods to be healthy. You can get the proper amino acids from eating a variety of plant protein sources such as
        beans, lentils, nuts, seeds, and soy as well as lower amounts in grains, vegetables, and fruits. Fat allows you to store
        energy, cushion organs, make certain hormones, absorb fat soluble vitamins, and helps with cell membrane integrity.
        There are three types of fat: trans fat, saturated fat, and unsaturated fat. Trans fat should be cut out of the diet.
        Most trans fat comes from hydrogenating or adding hydrogen molecules to unsaturated fats. This produces a hydrogenated oil.
        These can be found in margarine, shortening, baked goods, doughs, and fried foods. If you see trans fat on the label it
        should be avoided. Saturated fat does not have any bends, caused by double bonds, in the molecule because it is saturated in
        hydrogen molecules. In large amounts, saturated fat is known to increase cholesterol levels and can increase your risk for
        heart disease. Decreasing the amount of saturated fat in your diet can be beneficial. Saturated fat is found m with skin,
        lard, cream, butter, full fat cheese, and dairy. The American Heart Association recommends 5-6% of your daily kcals come
        from saturated fat; meaning if your kcal needs are 2,000 per day, only 120 kcals should come from saturated fat. 120 kcals/9
        kcals/g = ~13 grams of saturated fat per day. It is recommended that you decrease saturated fat intake and lean towards more healthy
        fats, known as unsaturated fats. Unsaturated fat has at least one double bond causing bends in the molecule. These are harder
        to stack and, therefore, are usually found in a liquid state at room temperature. The number of double bonds allows for the naming
        of unsaturated fats. Mono unsaturated fats have one double bond while Poly unsaturated fats have multiple or many. Unsaturated
        fats are known as the healthy fat as they can decrease your risk for heart disease. These healthy fats originate from plant sources
        such as avocados,nuts and nut butters, seeds, olives, and oils (olive, canola, safflower etc.). They can also be found in animal
        so fish including salmon, mackerel, sardines, tuna, and herring.</string>
>>>>>>> Stashed changes
</resources>